Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.2: Personal Correspondence and Administrative Files of Cordier
    - Sub-subseries V.2.6: Public Addresses & Papers, Honorary Degrees, Awards
      - 24 Mar 1960 Northrop Collegiate School, Minneapolis, Minn.. Visit to the UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 29 Mar 1960 Women's City Club of New York, 277 Park Ave. New York, luncheon. (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 2 Apr 1960 7th annual conference on International Education (Metropolitan Committee on International Education and the Middle States Council for Social Studies), The Carnegie Endowment International Center, and UN Hq, New York, N.Y. "Implications of 14th General Assembly" (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 7 Apr 1960 Overseas Writers Club, Washington, D.C.,(Willard Hotel) (Text on file: Yes, notes, edited) (Box 68)
      - 7 Apr 1960 Post Office Department, Washington, D.C. Ceremony dedicating the 4 cent World Refugee Year Commemorative Postage Stamp (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 7 Apr 1960 Friends General Conference,(subcom. on the UN Peace and Social Order Committee). Fourth Annual Conference at the UN. "Developing Role of the United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 9 Apr 1960 Church of the Brethren, group from Lancaster and Harrisburg areas (Pennsylvania) At UN Hq. New York (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 13 Apr 1960 Shortridge High School, Indianapolis, Indiana Visit to UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 14 Apr 1960 Indiana University, Division of University Extension, Indianapolis, Indiana. High School students, study group tour. Visit to UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 14 Apr 1960 Opening of World Refugee Year Stamp Exhibition, UN Uq., New York. Opened by Mr. Cordier in place of Secretary-General. (Resume in press release) (Box 68)
      - 16 Apr 1960 Munford High. School, Munford, Alabama; senior class--visit to UN Hq., New York (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 20 Apr 1960 United States Committee for the United Nations, Washington, D.C. (Meeting of Council of Member Organizations at the State Department) "The United Nations, An Assessment" (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 24 Apr 1960 Church of the. Brethren, UN Institute, Central Church, Roanoke, Virginia. "Operation UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 2 May 1960 International House, New York, N.Y. Rockefeller 35th anniversary dinner. Message from the Secretary-General given by Mr. Cordier. (Text on file: Yes) (Box 68)
      - 4 May 1960 New York University, New York, N.Y. School of Law (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 10 May 1960 University of Chicago Alumni,' UN Hq. New York (Text on file: No) (Box 68)
      - 18 May 1960 Canadian Institute of International Affairs, Montreal Branch, Montreal, Canada. "The United Nations in Perspective" (Text on file: No). Also CBC interview? (see Ir. on file) (Box 68)
      - 22 May 1960 Brethren Service Project, Castaner, Puerto Rico. Dedication of Castaner Hospital. Mr. Cordier message by AWC cancelled trip but sent message, see text. (Text on file: Yes, text of message by ACW) (Box 68)
      - 20 May 1960 Christian Century, Chicago, 111. t. Statements of Secretary-General and of Mr. Cordier on failure of summit meetings in Paris (Text on file: Yes) (Box 68)
      - May 1960 Guest Editorial, for IPMR a publication of the Yes Institute of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, New York, N.Y. (Text on file: Yes) (Box 68)
      - 15 Oct 1960 Fairleigh Dickinson University, Rutherford, N.J. Commencement address and honorary degree. "United-Nations-in-a-Changing-World" "UN Today" (Congo) (Edites and unedited texts on file) (Box 69)
      - 30 Oct 1960 New York Times Youth Forum, National Broadcasting Co., New York, N.Y. Topic: "The United Nations, the Congo and the Small Nations." Three files: 1. Correspondence with N.Y. Times, etc.; 2. Transcript of forum discussion; 3. Belgian reaction: press clips, correspondence with govt., other (Text on file: Yes, transcript) (Box 69)
      - 11 Dec 1960 Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (1); documentary with Tom Hamilton, 1 hour. (Project 61 series). Taped interview with Mr. Cordier. (Only a resume of suggested subjects for interview). (Box 69)
      - 18 Jan 1961 Men's Club, First Congregational" Church, Winchester, Mass. (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 25 Jan 1961 Nieman Foundation for Journalism, Harvard Univ. visit to UN Hq. New York. "Congo"? (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 3 Feb 1961 Church of the Brethren, Brooklyn, N.Y. Youth Group at UN Hq. (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 8 Feb 1961 Millikin University, Decatur, Illinois. Convocation speaker; Honorary Degree. Theme of address UN and the Congo. (?)(Text on file: Yes) (Box 69)
      - 8 Feb 1961 Church of the Brethren, Decatur, Illinois, supper NU meeting. "Responsible role of the Church in support of the UN" - a suggested topic? (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 8 Feb 1961 Decatur Chamber of Commerce, and Millikin Univ., co-sponsors, evening meeting. "The United Nations and the World Crisis" (Decatur, Illinois) (Text on file: Yes) (Box 69)
      - 25 Feb 1961 New York University, Conference on Critical Problems Before the 15th Session of the General Assembly, UN Headquarters, New York. (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 7 Mar 1961 Men's Class, of the Riverside Church, New York, N.Y., annual dinner. "The United Nations and the World Crisis". (live broadcast over Church Radio Station WRVR) (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 20 Mar 1961 United Nations Information Centre Directors at UN Hq., New York. Suggested topic:" Some major issues confronting the UN" (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 30 Apr 1961 Wilmington College, Wilmington, Ohio. Inauguration of Dr. James Read as President. "Crisis in the World Community" (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 2 May 1961 Conference Group of US National Organizations on the United Nations, annual meeting. UN Hq., New York. "Roundup of the Fifteenth General Assembly Session" (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 5 May 1961 International Law Association, American Branch, 'Annual Dinner, Cosmopolitan Club, New York City. (Box 69)
      - 15 May 1961 New York University and Carnegie Endowment for International Peace: 1961 Annual Review of United Nations Affairs. Held at Carnegie Building 345 E. 46th St. New York N.Y. "Role of the secretary-General" File #1: correspondence and working text. "Texts on File: #1 – 1. Texts prepared in advance for the panelists -- 2. Transcript of Mr. Cordier' s, talk and discussion period following (neither texts used in printed form) -- 3. Text as re-drafted by Mr. Cordier -- 4. Final revised text for printers -- 5. Printed text. File #2: Correspondence regarding Mr. Cordier's distribution of printed text. (Box 69)
      - 18 May 1961 National Conference of Christians and Jews, annual brotherhood dinner, Minneapolis, Minn. "Crisis in the World Community" (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 19 May 1961 Malone College, Canton, Ohio.--Dedication of Osborne Hall. (taped for rebroadcast over WHBC) (Text on file: No) (Box 69)
      - 4 Jun 1961 Lewis and Clark College, Portland, Oregon. Commencement address and Hon. Degree. "Crisis in the World Community" (also spoke Junior Chamber of Commerce at breakfast meeting; also appeared TV program international affairs?) (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 12 Jun 1961 Denison University, Granville, Ohio. Commencement address & Hon. Degree. " Crisis in the World Community" (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 16 Jun 1961 Collegiate Council for the United Nations Annual Intercollegiate Leadership Institute, UN Hq. Suggested topic: Implications of Increased Membership. (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 22 Jun 1961 Wingspread Briefing on the United Nations under the auspices of University of Wisconsin and the Johnson Foundation, Wingspread conference Center, Racine, Wisconsin. "Sixteen Years Development of the United Nations" (address & question period) (Partially edited transcript by AWC?) (Box 70)
      - 1 Jul 1961 National Education Association, visit to UN Hq. "The United Nations Today" (Box 70)
      - 11 Jul 1961 Colgate University, Hamilton, .N.Y. (Foreign .Policy Conference). "The United Nations and the Winds of Change" (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 11 Jul 1961 The Pennsylvania State University, group visit to UN Hq. (Box 70)
      - 2 Aug 1961 United Lutheran Church Men's Convention, at Wagner Lutheran College, Staten Island, N.Y. "The United Nations and the Winds of Change" (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - Sep 1961 Zionist Organization of America, Briefing Conference at UN Hq., New York, N.Y. (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - ? Sep 1961 New York Times Sunday Magazine; article entitled" Is the International Mind Possible" (Text on file: Yes, with working drafts) (Box 70)
      - 5 Oct 1961 American Association for the United Nations, special briefing on issues before the 16th general assembly; closed circuit telecast (through CBS). Done at UN Hq. Moderator­Richard Hottelet. (Hammarskjold, the Congo) (Text on file: Yes) (Box 70)
      - 24 October 1961. YMCA of Greater New York, annual dinner meeting at Hotel Astor, New York, N.Y. Presentation of citation to Mr Cordier. (Mr. Cordier's remarks taped but no copy on file) (Box 70)
      - 30 October 1961. The Biblical Seminary in New York. Lecture series: Christianity and World Revolution (Text on file: Yes, unedited typescript) (Box 70)
      - 6 November 1961. Dillon Lecturer, State University of South Dakota, Vermillion, South Dakota. Two lectures: "The United Nations and the Winds of Change" and "The Congo, an Example of International Effort" (Text on file: Yes, both texts were combined for printed version in South Dakota Law Review) (Box 70)
      - 11 November 1961. International Fellows Program, Columbia University, New York, visit to UN Hq., New York. (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 14 November 1961. National Council of Jewish Women, United Nations Institute, UN Hq., New York. Presentation of scroll to Mr. Cordier as well as bronze candelabrum. "The United Nations and the Winds of Change" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 70)
      - 19 November 1961. The New York Times Youth Forum, NBC, New York City. Topic: "How Does Youth Feel about the United Nations?" (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 20 November 1961. Fairleigh Dickinson University, Rutherford, N.J., dinner meeting. (discussion) (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 8 December 1961. Fairleight Dickinson University,' students from Teaneck Campus, UN Seminar, visit to UN Hq., New York. (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 12 December 1961. New York University, School of Law. Pomeroy Scholars dinner. "United Nations" (Text on file: No) (Box 70)
      - 17 Jan 1962 United Nations Association in Canada, Toronto Yes (but excerpts Branch. Inside the UN luncheon series, only) Crystal Ballroom, King Edward Hotel, Toronto. "The United. Nations 'and the Winds of Change" (Live broadcast by Canadian Broadcasting Corp) (Text on file: Yes, but excerpts only) (Box 71)
      - 23 Jan 1962 National Council of Churches, luncheon honoring Mr, Cordier Carnegie International Centre, New York, N.Y. Recipient. of the first Walter W.Van Kirk Award for Christian Statesmanship, Remarks in response. (Text on file: Yes) (Box 71)
      - 28 January 1962. Manchester College Alumni group, Detroit, Mich.(Cregar's Pickwick House). (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 29 January 1962. Economic Club of Detroit, United Nations Luncheon, Veterans Memorial Building, Detroit. The United Nations in our Changing World. (Text on file: Yes, transcript and "excerpts" text) (Box 71)
      - 29 January 1962. 43rd Annual Ohio Pastors Convention, Veterans Memorial Building, Columbus, Ohio. "The Spiritual and Moral Problems of America's Role in the World" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 1 February 1962. The Conference of US National Organizations of the United Nations, annual luncheon; guest of honour, Mr. Cordier. Carnegie Building, New York, N.Y. "Roundup of Sixteenth General Assembly Session" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 9 February 1962. Annual Ohio Newspaper Association banquet, Columbus, Ohio. Recipient of the Governor's Award, presented by the Governor of Ohio. Michael DiSalle (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 9 February 1962. Muskingum College, New Concord Ohio. Lecture (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 16 February 1962. Secretariat News, United Nations. Text of Mr. Cordier's farewell message to the UN Staf(Text on file: Yes) (Box 71)
      - 17 February 1962. New York University, 1962 Conference on Critical Problems before the Sixteenth General Assembly. UN Hq.,. New York. (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 25 February 1962. "People at the 'United Nations": interview by Celeste Holme, WNBC (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - During the period March-June 1962 Mr. Cordier was between career posts, i.e. he concluded his service with the United Nations at the end of February 1962 and began his career at Columbia University as Dean of the School of International Affairs on 1 July 1962. (Box 71)
      - 2 March 1962. Indianapolis Council on World Affairs, Indianapolis, Indiana. "America's Stake in World Affairs" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 2 Mar 1962 Indiana University, Bloomington, Ind. Little United Nations Assembly Convocation. "The United Nations in a World of Tension and Revolution" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 5 and 6 March 1962. University of Chicago, Norman Wait Harris Memorial Foundation in International Relations, 2 lectures. Chicago, Illinois Topics:-The United Nations and the Winds of Change". --"The Congo, an example of World Tensions and International Effort" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 7 March 1962 Association for Higher Education (National trans­Education Association). 17th annual nat. cript, roughly edited conon Higher Education, Morrison Hotel, by Mr. Cordier.Resume Chicago, Ill. "The United Nations. And the Winds of Change(Yes, text of transcript roughly edited by Mr. Cordier. Resume only used for published proceeding) (Box 71)
      - 10 Mar 1962 Eternal Light Program, NBC New York. (Mr. Cordier's remarks taped at UN Hq. 27 Feb 1962) (Box 71)
      - 11 Mar 1962 American Association for the United Nations, Conference of National Organizatiotns, Statler Hilton Hotel, Washington, D.C. "Sixteenth Session of the General Assembly" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 71)
      - 15 Mar 1962 National Council of Churches, Dept. of Int. Affairs, Riverside Church, New York, N.Y. "Review and Preview of UN Developments" (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - May 1962 Bilderberg Meetings, Stockholm, Sweden "The Political Implications for the Atlantic Community of its Members' Policies in the United Nations Concerning Relations with the Developing Countries" (Text on file: Yes) (Box 71)
      - 8 June 1962 Haverford College, Haverford, 'Pennsylvania Honorary degree. (Contents catalogued: Borton Hugh) (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 9 Jun 1962 Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo,. Mich. Commencement address and honorary degree. (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 20 Jun 1962 Mutual Admiration Society, New York, N.Y.Luncheon (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 21 Jun 1962 Annual Conferenee of Church of the Brethren, Elgin, Illinois (Text on file: No) (Box 71)
      - 22 Jun 1962 Association of Council of Churches Secretaries. Williams Bay, Lake' Geneva, Wisconsin (Box 71)
      - Speech Source Material (Box 71)
      - Speech Log, 1958-1962 (Box 71)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.7: Personal
      - Invitations To Speak (Regrets Sent): (Box 71)
      - Vol. IA 1946-1948 (Box 72)
      - Vol. I 1949 (Box 72)
      - Vol. II 1950 (Box 72)
      - Vol. III 1951 (Box 72)
      - Vol. VIII 1956 (Box 73)
      - IV 1952 (Box 73)
      - Vol. V 1953 (Box 73)
      - Vol. VI 1954 (Box 73)
      - Vol. VII 1955 (Box 73)
      - Vol. IX 1957 (Box 73)
      - Vol. X 1958 (Box 73)
      - Vol. XI 1959 (Box 74)
      - Vol. XII 1960 (Box 74)
      - Vol. XIII 1961 (Box 74)
      - Vol. XIV. 1962 (Box 74)
      - Role of the Secretary-General, (3 Folders) (Box 74)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.8: AWC Official Trip Files
      - Travel instructional memos 1951-1961 (Box 75)
      - Travel 1946-1948 General file (authorizations, claims, etc.:) (Box 75)
      - Travel 1949 General file (Box 75)
      - Travel 1950 Genera1 file (Box 75)
      - Travel 1951. General file (authorizations, claims, etc.) (Box 75)
      - May-June 1951 Round the world trip (Tokyo, Korea, Bangkok, India, Pakistan, Cairo, Paris): (Box 75)
      - Press clippings Folder (Box 75)
      - Brown Folder containing following files:
        - Cables general (Box 75)
        - Cables, substantive (Box 75)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 75)
        - Press release on trip (Box 75)
        - Travel itinerary (Box 75)
        - Trip report (by Protitch) (Box 75)
        - India-Pakistan (Kashmir) (Box 75)
        - Korea:. background paper on economic aid etc (Box 75)
        - Korea: background paper on inflation (Box 75)
        - Korea: forced landing, accident report (Box 75)
        - Korea: Press releases, radio interviews .. (Box 75)
        - Korea: UN Commission for Unification and Rehabilitation of Korea: meeting 25 May 1951 (Box 75)
        - Tokyo: Korea: Itineraries, programs, persons met, etc. (Box 75)
        - Tokyo: Korea: Guides (UN Guide to Tokyo), scrip, other (Box 75)
        - Photographs. chiefly Korea Mr. Cordier addressing Unified Command troops, etc.) (very .good) (Box 76)
      - Travel 1952
        - General file (authorizations, claims, etc.) (Box 76)
        - March-April 1952. Round the world trip (Tokyo, Korea, India, Pakistan, Beirut, Geneva):
          - Cables (Box 76)
          - Correspondence, memos, itinerary, etc. (Box 76)
          - Vouchers, certificates, other misc. (Box 76)
          - Korea-Tokyo Background papers (Box 76)
          - Korea-Tokyo Invitations, activities, maps (Box 76)
          - Korea Photographs (very good) (Box 76)
          - Korea Press clippings (Box 76)
          - Korea Press interviews, press releases, texts of speeches (Box 76)
      - Travel 1953 --General file (authorizations, claims, etc.) (Box 77)
      - Travel 1954 General file (authorizations, claims, itinerary) (Box 77)
      - San Francisco re 10th Anniversary Commemorative Session (Nov 1954) (Box 77)
      - Travel 1955 General file (authorizations, claims, itineraries, etc.) (Box 77)
      - Travel 1956
        - 1) General file (authorizations, claims, etc.) (Box 77)
        - 2) 5-31 August 1956 Europe and Middle East(Visits to new member states):
          - "Background papers, (3 Folders) (Box 77)
          - General correspondence file (Box 77)
          - Confidential correspondence (reporting Mrs. Malania to Cordier) (Box 77)
          - Itinerary, 5-31 August 1956 (Box 77)
          - Press Release on trip (Box 77)
          - Spare copies (Box 77)
          - Individual correspondence files (places visited) (*=New member state)
            - Austria* (Box 77)
            - Beirut (Box 77)
            - Bulgaria* (Box 77)
            - Cairo (Box 77)
            - Geneva (Box 77)
            - Hungary* (Box 77)
            - Istanbul (Box 77)
            - Ireland* (Box 77)
            - Italy* (Box 77)
            - Jerusalem (Photos) (Box 77)
            - Jordan* (Box 77)
            - London (Box 77)
            - Paris (Box 77)
            - Portugal* (Box 77)
            - Romania* (Box 77)
            - Spain* (Box 77)
        - *Egypt: (Box 78)
          - 25 Dec 1956-1 Jan 1957 (Box 78)
          - *Cables, code and clear (Box 78)
          - Photo AWC (Box 78)
          - Press Clippings (Box 78)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 78)
      - Travel 1957
        - General file (authorizations, claims, itineraries, etc.) (Box 78)
      - Travel 1958
        - General file (authorizations, claims, itineraries, etc.) (Box 78)
        - Middle East 11-29 June 1958 (Beirut, Jerusalem). Representative of Secretary-General re demilitarization of Mount Scopus. (Box 78)
        - (Press release, correspondence, itinerary) (Box 78)
      - Travel 1959
        - General file (authorizations, claims, etc. Includes list of 1959 travel Jan-Oct 1959) (Box 78)
      - Travel 1960
        - General file (authorizations, claims, etc. Includes list of 1960 travel Feb-Sep 1960) (Box 78)
        - Congo trip Aug-Sep 1960 (itinerary, press releases) (Box 78)
      - Travel 1961
        - General file (authorizations, claims, etc. Includes list of 1961 travel) London, Middle East, Geneva May-Jun 1961 (Box 78)
        - Press releases, itinerary, cables, correspondence) (Box 78)
      - Travel 1962
        - General file (authorizations, claims, etc. No list of travel). (Box 78)
      - Daily Calendars:
        - 1950 (May-December only) (Box 79)
        - 1951 (New York: Jan-October. Paris: Oct.-Dec (General Assembly) (some gaps) 1952 (Paris: Jan-Feb (General Assembly) (Box 79)
        - 1952 (New York: Feb-Dec) (Box 79)
        - 1953 (Box 79)
        - 1954 (Box 79)
        - 1955 (Box 79)
        - 1956 (Box 80)
        - 1957 (Box 80)
        - 1958 (Box 80)
        - 1959 (Box 80)
        - 1960 (Box 80)
        - 1961 (Box 80)
        - 1962 (Jan-Mar) (Box 80)
  - Subseries V.3: United Nations Administration
    - Sub-subseries V.3.1: Administrative Matters
      - Absences of the Secretaries-General (memos) (Box 81)
      - Cordier "Administrative memos" (Box 81)
      - Committees. boards. panels. etc. of UN Secretariat:
        - Arbitration, UN Panel of (Box 81)
        - Building Changes, Committee on (Box 81)
        - Circulation of Communications, Committee on (Box 81)
        - Contracts, Committee on (Box 81)
        - *(RESTRICTED) Economic Policy Board (Box 81)
        - Exhibitions, Committee on (Box 81)
        - Office Records am Equipment (Box 81)
        - Outer Space, Secretariat Study Group (Box 81)
        - Property Survey Board (Box 81)
        - Revenues, Committee on (Box 81)
        - Travel of Staff Members, Policy & Procedures (Box 81)
      - Thomas Cook & Son (Box 81)
      - Correspondence memoranda and manual (Box 81)
      - Documentation, Limitation of (Box 81)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Economic Commission for Africa (Addis Ababa) Cables 1960-62 (Box 81)
      - European Office of the United Nations, Geneva (Box 81)
      - *(RESTRICTED) Cables, code, 1961-1962: (Box 82)
        - Foreign Ministers Conference 1959 cables (Box 82)
        - USSR gift proposal (Box 82)
      - Flag Code (Box 82)
      - International Civil Service Advisory Board (Box 82)
      - International Civil Servants Association (Box 82)
      - Khrushchev visit 1959 arrangements (Box 82)
      - Permanent Headquarters, New York
        - Headquarters Agreement( memos, correspondence) (Box 82)
        - Architects, Committee of (Box 82)
        - Architects' drawings: General Assembly, Secretariat, Meeting Halls (Box 82)
        - Cornerstone ceremony (Box 82)
        - Garage (Box 83)
        - General Assembly Building (Box 83)
        - General correspondence file (Box 83)
        - Gifts (Box 83)
        - Guide Service (Box 83)
        - Meditation Room (Box 84)
        - Meetings (Box 84)
        - Use by outside organizations (Box 84)
        - U.S. Government loan (Box 84)
      - Special Allowances, Under Secretaries 1955-1961 (Box 84)
      - Terminology (Box 84)
      - UN Co-op Inc. (Box 85)
      - UN Gallery (Derso) (Box 85)
      - UN International School: (Box 85)
      - To 1955, (4 Folders) (Box 85)
      - Reports (Box 85)
      - UN International Co-operative Community (Box 86)
      - UN Postal Administration:
        - General file (Box 86)
        - Case of sale of unused pre-cancelled stamps (Box 86)